Curatorial Correspondence, 1920-1961
Smithsonian Institution Archives
Curatorial Correspondence
1920-1961
Smithsonian Institution Archives, Washington, D.C., osiaref@si.edu
United States National Museum, Division of Phanerogams
SI Records
0.4 linear meter.
Record Unit 230
Historical Note
Emery Clarence Leonard (1892-1968) was born in Ohio and attended Wittenberg College. He did his postgraduate work at Ohio State University. In January 1918 he was made an aid in the United States National Museum, Division of Plants (which became the Department of Botany in 1947), and went on military furlough six months later. Leonard returned to the Smithsonian in July 1919. From 1928 to 1936 he was assistant curator, Division of Plants, and from 1937 to 1962 was associate curator, Department of Botany, Division of Phanerogams. Leonard retired in 1962 and was made research associate, Division of Phanerogams.
Introduction
This finding aid was digitized with funds generously provided by the Smithsonian Institution Women's Committee.
Descriptive Entry
These records consist of mostly incoming and outgoing correspondence with botanists; colleagues; friends; herbarium curators; directors of arboreta; private collectors of plants; and publishers; and they concern specimen identification; recommendation of books to be used for identification of plants; requests for reprints; purchase and acquisition of collections; reference to colleagues and herbariums; history of private collections; also includes some personal accounts of daily activity of friends and colleagues and personal memorandum regarding Leonard's salary, upgrading, and recommendation that he be made a research associate.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following access terms. These are links to collections with related topics, persons or places.
Name
Leonard, Emery C.; United States National Museum. Division of Plants
Subject
Botany
- Box 1
  - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1920-1961. Loose. Arranged Alphabetically.
  - A-B (Box 1 of 2)
  - Allard, Harry Ardell (1947-1960) (Box 1 of 2)
  - Arnold, Lillian E. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Bailey, Liberty Hyde (1943-1944) (Box 1 of 2)
  - Baker, R. E. D. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Bartley, Floyd (Box 1 of 2)
  - Bartram, Edwin Bunting (1940-1944) (Box 1 of 2)
  - Blair, J. B. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Bold, Harold C. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Booth, O. E. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Burkett, Lindon (Box 1 of 2)
  - C-D (Box 1 of 2)
  - Carl, Helmut (Box 1 of 2)
  - Castle, H. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Channell, T. B. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Chardon, Carlos E. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Chase, Virginius H. (1946-1948) (Box 1 of 2)
  - Cochran, D. M. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Conard, H. S. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Core, Earl L. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Correll, Donovan S. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Croizat, Leon (1944, 1948) (Box 1 of 2)
  - Curtis, J. T. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Curtiss, Anthony (Box 1 of 2)
  - Davis, H. A. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Dechenes, J. A. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Demaree, Delzie (Box 1 of 2)
  - DeSelm, H. R. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Dickerson, L. M. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Dodge, Carroll W. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Douglas, Marshall (Box 1 of 2)
  - E-G (Box 1 of 2)
  - Edingfield, G. H. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Evans, Alexander William (1932-1956) (Box 1 of 2)
  - Ewan, Joseph (1951-1952) (Box 1 of 2)
  - Foster, M. B. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Fulford, Margaret (Box 1 of 2)
  - Garcia-Barriga, Hernando (Box 1 of 2)
  - Gates, Burton N. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Gentry, Howard Scott (Box 1 of 2)
  - Gleason, Henry Allan (1955) (Box 1 of 2)
  - Grant, William F. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Gualbert, Fr. M. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Guild, William (Box 1 of 2)
  - H-K (Box 1 of 2)
  - Hanson, Craig A. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Harper, R. M. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Holdridge, Leslie R. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Howard, Richard Alden (1947-1958) (Box 1 of 2)
  - Iltis, Hugh H. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Irvine, F. R. (Box 1 of 2)
  - Jones, Samuel B. (Box 1 of 2)
- Box 2
  - Kiem, Stanley C. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Killip, Ellsworth Paine (1925-1957) (Box 2 of 2)
  - King, J. Cecil (1957-1959) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Knobloch, Irving W. (Box 2 of 2)
  - L-N (Box 2 of 2)
  - Langman, Ida K. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Lawrence, George H. M. (1948-1950) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Leonard, Emery Clarence (1939-1961). Personal folder that includes memoranda on Leonard's upgrading and recommendation that he be made honorary research associate. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Leonard, John (Box 2 of 2)
  - Leonard, M. D. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Lundell, C. L. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Lutz, Bertha (Box 2 of 2)
  - Macedo, A. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Massey, A. B. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Maxon, William Ralph (1934-1948) (Box 2 of 2)
  - McAtee, W. L. (Box 2 of 2)
  - McCrary, O. F. (Box 2 of 2)
  - McVaugh, Rogers (Box 2 of 2)
  - Merrill, Luella (Box 2 of 2)
  - Meyer, Fred G. (1948-1953) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Millar, John R. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Miller, William E. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Moldenke, Harold Norman (1941-1951) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Monachino, Joseph (Box 2 of 2)
  - Moore, Harold E. (1950-1959) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Murrill, W. A. (Box 2 of 2)
  - O-R (Box 2 of 2)
  - Patterson, Paul Morrison (1948-1949) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Peacock, M. B. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Pennell, Francis Whittier (1944-1950) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Penny, John S. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Petro, James H. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Proctor, George H. (1950-1959) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Raghavan, V. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Rambo, B. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Reed, Clyde T. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Reig, Siri von (Box 2 of 2)
  - Robison, William C. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Rollins, Reed C. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Rood, Almon N. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Rzedowski, J. (Box 2 of 2)
  - S-Z (Box 2 of 2)
  - Sandwith, N. Y. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Sargent, F. H. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Sharp, A. J. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Slama, Frank J. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Smith, Harry L. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Smith, Lyman B. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Stafleu, F. A. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Standley, Paul Carpenter (1920, 1925, 1941-1948) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Stehle, H. (in Spanish) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Stearns, J. L. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Steere, William Campbell (1935-1952) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Steyermark, Julian A. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Sucheron, William (Box 2 of 2)
  - Theofanis, Thomas (Box 2 of 2)
  - Thomson, John W. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Uribe, Lorenzo Uribe (Box 2 of 2)
  - Vannorsdall, H. H. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Velez, Ismael (Box 2 of 2)
  - Webster, Grady L. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Weishaupt, Clara (Box 2 of 2)
  - White, Orland E. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Wiggins, Ira L. (Box 2 of 2)
  - Williams, Louis Otho (1948-1952) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Woodson, Robert Everard Jr. (1949-1960) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Youngken, Heber Wilkinson (1955-1957) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Yust, Walter (1958) (Box 2 of 2)
  - Zerkel, Waldo (Box 2 of 2)